(銀時)
何これって 見りゃわかんだろ｡
ふっかつのじゅもんが
必要なんだよ！
つうか この呪文
どっかで見たことなくね？
いや それもう ｹﾞｰﾑ違うし…｡
｢ふっかつのじゅもん｣だよ
ふっかつのじゅもん｡
先週の続きすんだろ？
当然 必要じゃん｡
(新八)って… え？ 何これ？
今どき こんな前時代のﾊﾟｽﾜｰﾄﾞｼｽﾃﾑ
ねえだろう！
いや
適当じゃまずいでしょ 適当じゃ｡
つうか 『銀魂』関係ない人
交じってなくね？
何お前？ ﾒﾓ取ってなかったの？
ね～よ！
なんでだよ！
なんでｱﾆﾒの前話回想するのに➡
しかたねえなぁ｡
じゃあ 適当に入力すっか｡
よし 終了っと｡
いいんだよ｡ こういうのは
だいたいﾊﾟﾀｰﾝがあんの｡
つうか 先週のﾗｽﾄで
ひと言も呪文出てなかったよ！
おい！ なんか違うｹﾞｰﾑ
始まってんですけど！
｢上 上 下 下 左 右 左 右 Ｂ Ａ｣
みたいなもんだよ｡
いつのｹﾞｰﾑだよ これ！
元ﾈﾀ 今の子わかんねえだろ これ｡
♪♪～
[Last time on GinTama:]
つうか ﾀﾏさん何やってんの!?
はい ｸﾘｱ｡ ﾀﾏ編 終了っと｡
[Input the damn resurrection spell]
[Note: Parody of Dragon Quest game.]
Uh, wait. What is this?
犯人はﾀﾏ｡
はやっ！
Can't you tell?
つうか んなわけねえだろ！
全然 先週と話つながってねえよ！
It's a "resurrection spell," okay?
どこだよ!? ﾀﾏﾄﾋﾟｱ｡
もう少し ﾏｼﾞﾒに始めろ！
We're picking up where we
left off last week, right?
So we need one.
Why?!
Why do we need a "resurrection spell" for an
anime flashback of the previous episode?!
Nobody uses a password system
in this day and age!
And a spell was never mentioned
at the end of last week's episode!
What? You didn't write it down?
There wasn't one!
You're so useless.
Then I'll just enter something random.
Uh, I'm pretty sure it's a bad
idea to put in random stuff.
It'll be fine.
[KAGURA SHINPACHI GINTOKI
AMACHI HIDEAKI HORI RYUUJI]
[Note: HORI RYUUJI is a parody of Yuji Horii,
creator of Dragon Quest.]
There's usually a pattern to these things.
Like an Up, Up, Down, Down, Left,
Right, Left, Right, B, A kind of thing.
[Note: The famous Konami Code to get 9
extra lives in Nintendo's Contra.]
Uh, that'd be a totally different game.
And doesn't this spell
look awfully familiar?
And aren't you including people who
have nothing to do with GinTama?
Okay, all done.
[Tama: I am your subordinate
Please call me Tama]
Hey!
A different game has started up!
[Tama: We are in Edo in the vicinity where the incident
occurred How do you wish to begin the investigation?]
How ancient is this thing?!
Kids nowadays wouldn't be
able to recognize this!
[(Selects Confession)]
[Tama: Then I shall confess first]
And what the hell is Tama-san doing?!
[Tama: Forgive me I did it Tama was the culprit]
[Tama: I'll never do it again Please forgive me]
Okay, all clear.
Tama's the killer.
[Tamatopia Murder Case
The End]
Tama was the culprit.
That was fast!
And that's not even possible!
That had nothing to do with
last week's episode!
Where the hell is Tamatopia?!
[Note: Parody of Portopia Serial Murder
Case. Created by Yuji Horii.]
Can't you be serious about this?!
[The real recap from last episode.]
The computer virus "Tapir."
(源外)電脳ｳｲﾙｽ ｢獏｣｡
ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑにとりつき
それを喰らうように➡
A brand-new virus that infects the program,
consumes it, and multiplies.
増殖肥大化する 最新型ｳｲﾙｽ｡
超高度な からくり技術を施された
｢たま｣に侵入した時点で➡
Once it infected Tama, who
is a highly advanced robot,
相当に
育ったﾔﾂだったんだろうが➡
it must have evolved a great deal.
さらに そこに長く潜伏したんだ｡
And it's been there for a while.
もはや 誰の手にも負えねえ
最悪最強のｳｲﾙｽになっていようよ｡
Nobody can do anything about it.
It's evolved into the strongest
and worst virus ever.
だが まだ一つだけ
たまを助ける方法がある｡
But there's still a way to save Tama.
決まってんだろう｡
Shouldn't that be obvious?
ｳｲﾙｽを駆逐するんだよ｡
ﾃﾒｴら 一寸法師が｡
We're going to eliminate the virus.
You midgets are doing it.
じゃ 健闘を祈る！
Best of luck to you.
["The Human Body is Like a Little Universe"]
ようこそ 白血球国へ｡
Welcome to Leukocyte Kingdom.
[Note: Leukocytes are the white blood cells
that defend the body from infections.]
ここから北に進むと白血球城
東に行くとﾋﾞﾌｨｽﾞｽ菌村➡
If you head north, you will
find Leukocyte Castle.
Head east to find Bifidus Village.
南に行くと大腸菌の町があるぞ｡
Head south to find E. coli town.
[Leukocyte Kingdom]
だが西の毛細血管の洞窟には
近づくな｡ ｳｲﾙｽの巣窟だ｡
But stay away from the Capillary
Caves to the west.
It's crawling with viruses.
お前たちのﾚﾍﾞﾙでは
あっという間に全滅だぞ｡
At your current level, you'll
be instantly wiped out.
(新八)
えっ… 何？ 何この人たち？
Huh?
What?
What's with these people?
えっ… 何ここ？
Huh?
What's with this place?
何これ!!
なんで たまさんの中に➡
What is this?!
Why are all these people in bodysuits wandering
around inside Tama-san's body?!
全身ﾀｲﾂの人間が
ｳﾛｳﾛしてんですか!?
なんで たまさんの中に
全身ﾀｲﾂの国があるんですか!?
Why is there an entire nation
inside of Tama-san?!
なんで武器屋があるの!?
なんで宿屋があるの!?
Why is there a weapon shop?!
Why is there an inn?!
Why is this like an RPG?!
なんで ＲＰＧ風なの!?
って銀さん！ どこ行く気ですか？
Uh, Gin-san?
Where are you two going?
(銀時)決まってんだろ｡
ほら あれだろ｡
Shouldn't that be obvious?
The first step when you come to one of these
places is to put together a war chest.
こういうとこ来たら
基本 軍資金が必要だろ｡
だからさ…｡
That's why...
って なんで
いきなりｶｼﾞﾉ来てんですか！
Why did you head straight
for the casino?!
だから 軍資金作るんだって｡
I just said we needed a war chest.
お金足りない綱渡りな冒険は
避けたいじゃん｡
I don't want to deal with a riskily run adventure
where we're always strapped for cash.
ｵﾚは ＲＰＧする時➡
I'm the kind of person who spends hours
ついつい ﾐﾆｹﾞｰﾑばっか
何時間もやっちゃうﾀｲﾌﾟなんだよ｡
on the mini games whenever
I play an RPG.
そうやって ｹﾞｰﾑでもﾘｱﾙでも
寄り道ばっかに力 入れてるから➡
You can't make any progress that way
because you always get off track,
なかなか先に進まないんですよ！
in-game and in real life!
The next thing you know, you've
forgotten the main story!
気づいたら
ﾒｲﾝｼﾅﾘｵ忘れてるんですよ！
つうか こんなとこで
遊んでるﾋﾏないからね！
We don't have time to play around here!
早くしないと
たまさんが どんどん➡
Tama-san will be taken over by more
of the virus if we don't hurry!
ｳｲﾙｽに侵されていくんですから！
Calm down, Shinpachi.
(神楽)落ち着け 新八｡
ｶﾈなくて お前➡
You realize that without any money,
装備が ひのきの眼鏡のままで
いいｱﾙか？
[Note: Parody of the Cypress Stick (starter
weapon) from Dragon Quest game.]
you'll have to stay equipped with
those Cypress Glasses?
何だよ ひのきの眼鏡って！
What the hell are Cypress Glasses?!
次の町で
銅の眼鏡 買えなくていいｱﾙか？
Don't you want to buy Steel
Glasses at the next town?
まあまあ 一回 心を静めてさ｡
急いては事を仕損じるよ｡
Now, now.
Calm down for now.
It's a waste to rush through everything.
ＲＰＧは 冒険に出る前の
下準備が大事だから｡
It's important to prepare well before setting
out on an adventure in an RPG.
知らないよ｡ 町出て
いきなり強敵に出くわしても｡
Don't blame me if you leave the safe town
and run into a really strong enemy.
では 神の前に
これまでの行いを告白しなさい｡
Now confess what you've
done before God.
って ｾｰﾌﾞしてる場合か!?
まだ何もしてねえよ！
We're saving right now?!
We haven't done anything yet!
ｶｼﾞﾉ行っただけだよ！
何が不満ね？
All we did was go to the casino!
What's your beef?
そうか… 新八は ｾｰﾌﾞ前は➡
I see.
Shinpachi's the type who always
rests up at an inn before saving?
必ず宿屋で
体力全部 回復する派か｡ ﾏﾒだな｡
You're a real stickler.
いちいち こんな所でｾｰﾌﾞしてる
お前らがﾏﾒだ！
You people are the sticklers! Who
bothers to save at this point?!
つうか 話 進めろ！
Just move on with the story!
ｱﾝﾀら ﾎﾞｸの話 聞いてた!?
急がなきゃいけないんですよ｡
Were you listening to me?
We need to hurry.
早くしないと
取り返しがつかないんですよ！
If we don't pick up the
pace, we'll be too late.
I know that.
わかってるよ…
あれじゃねえか？
But y'know?
We're completely clueless right now.
右も左も
わかんねえんだぞ ｵﾚたち｡
むやみやたらに動いても
しかたねえだろう｡
There's no point in floundering around.
お前 どうすればいいか
わかってんの？
Do you know what we're
supposed to do?
ほら見ろ… なんつっても ここは
ｵﾚたちにとっては完全にｱｳｪｲだ｡
See?
After all, we're completely
out of our comfort zone.
ｺｲﾂらだって敵か味方か
まったくもってわからねえんだぜ｡
We have no idea if these guys
are allies or enemies.
確かにそうですけど…｡
You have a point...
(たま)ご安心ください｡
Do not worry.
They all serve me.
た… たまさん!?
Ta-Tama-san!
Allow me to guide you.
Could you please follow me?
なに!? たまさんの中に
たまさんまで出てきたよ！
What?!
Tama-san showed up inside Tama-san!
I apologize for taking so long.
I created an offshoot from a sector
in my system that is still safe.
I shall provide you with support.
ｻﾎﾟｰﾄって…｡ 大丈夫なんですか!?
たまさんの体のほうは…｡
Provide us with support?
Is your body okay?!
There is no problem.
I cannot lie around shamelessly while
everyone else is fighting for my sake.
やぁ すみません｡
まだ ｶｼﾞﾉ行ったりとかで➡
Er, sorry about that...
We've only been to the casino, so we
haven't actually done any fighting.
ろくに戦えてないです｡
I shall redirect the remaining operational
systems to support you.
まさか ｺｲﾂらも!?
Does that include these guys?!
Yes, they are components of the original
security system in my body.
(たま)対ｳｲﾙｽﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑ 白血球です｡
ｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰ!? この全身ﾀｲﾂが!?
The anti-virus program, Leukocyte.
Security?! These men in bodysuits?!
彼らは私の体内に
侵入したｳｲﾙｽを駆除するのが役目｡
Their job is to expel the viruses
that infiltrate my body.
こうして私の体内に巣を作り
私を守ってくれているのです｡
And as they protect me, they've also
built a home inside my body.
守ってくれてるって…
本当にこれ 守ってるんですか？
Protect you...?
Are they actually protecting you?
ﾄﾞﾗｸｴごっこやってるふうにしか
見えないんですけど…｡
It looks more like they're pretending
to be in Dragon Quest.
There is no problem.
(たま)彼らのﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑは みなさんが
この世界を救いにきた➡
Their program has been rewritten to recognize
you as saviors from another world.
勇者であると認識するよう
書き換えておきました｡
みな 惜しみなくｳｲﾙｽ退治を
手伝ってくれるはずです｡
They should all assist you
in destroying the viruses.
We should start by meeting with the Leukocyte
King and asking for his aid.
It will be impossible to defeat
the Tapir without it.
そうだ！ ﾎﾞｸら 考えたら
王様への伝言も頼まれてましたね｡
Oh, yeah.
Now that you mention it, we were asked
to deliver a message to the king.
((残念ながら
ｳｲﾙｽ軍を前に我ら白血球軍は壊滅｡
It saddens me to say that our Leukocyte
army has fallen to the Virus army.
願わくば 王だけでも
ここからお逃げいただきたい｡
I pray that our king takes flight.
そして 古くから伝わる
伝統の異界の戦士➡
And searches for the legendary
warriors from another world...
一寸法師をお探しください と…))
Search for the midgets...
行きましょう 銀さん…｡
Let's go, Gin-san.
♪♪～
おぉ～ ﾄﾝﾇﾗ｡
死んでしまうとは情けない｡
Tonnelat, how could you die on me?
[Note: Character name from Dragon Quest.]
No, he isn't dead.
いや 死んでねえよ｡
勝手に殺してんじゃねえよ｡
Don't kill him off like that.
つうか ﾄﾝﾇﾗって
どんだけﾀﾞﾒそうな名前だよ｡
And Tonnelat is one lame name.
次のﾚﾍﾞﾙに上がるまで ﾄﾝﾇﾗは➡
Tonnelat only needed 1,008 love experience
points to reach the next level.
あと1008ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄの
恋愛経験値が必要だ｡
What are love experience points?
何だよ？ その恋愛経験値って｡
How many times does a girl have to fail
at love before she grows stronger?
何度 恋に破れたら
女の子は強くなるんだよ｡
And who's Tonnelat?
つうか ﾄﾝﾇﾗって誰だよ！
Suke-san needs 5,466 more
summer experience points.
[Note: Fictional name from Dragon Quest.]
すけさんは あと5466ﾎﾟｲﾝﾄの
ひと夏の経験が必要だ｡
What the hell?!
何それ!? どんだけ
ひと夏 過ごしてんだよ！
How many summers has
he been through?!
ていうか なんで すけさん!?
And why Suke-san?!
Would you like to learn the
resurrection spell for love?
恋の復活の呪文を
聞いていくかね？
Only weak men would
be interested in that.
(神楽)そんなの聞きたいのは
引きずってる男だけよ｡
Women are always looking
forward to their next love!
女は いつでも
次の恋にまっしぐらある！
When did this game turn
into a romance RPG?
いつからこのｹﾞｰﾑ 恋愛ＲＰＧ
なんてｼﾞｬﾝﾙになったんだ！
どんだけ
恋の思い出に左右されてんだ！
Are you completely influenced
by your memories of love?!
痛い！ 痛い！
心に残る あの子の言葉が痛い！
Ow! Ow!
Her parting words are piercing my heart!
知るか！
Like I care!
何だと!? 我が白血球軍が
ｳｲﾙｽ軍に敗北したと申すか！
What did you say?!
You mean our Leukocyte army was
defeated by the Virus army?!
はい｡ 傷ついた兵士の
最後の伝言です｡
Yes.
That was the last message
from the injured soldier.
できれば ｳｲﾙｽの魔の手が
この国に迫る前に➡
He wished for Your Majesty to escape before
your foes reached your kingdom.
王様も逃げてほしいと…｡
But running away from love
will only lead to regret.
しかし 恋から逃げるのは
いつか後悔するものだぞ｡
もう ﾃﾒｴ 恋話から離れろよ！
どんだけ高校２年生だよ!!
Can you drop the crap
about love already?!
Are you a sophomore in high
school or something?!
この国のために戦い 傷ついた
白血球たちを残し逃げる｡
Escape and abandon the leukocytes who've
been injured while fighting for this kingdom?
なぜ
そのようなことができようか｡
How could I do such a thing?
旅の人よ… この国には古くから
こんな言い伝えがあるのだ｡
Travelers...
A legend has been passed down
in this kingdom from olden days.
この地に おおいなる災い
ふりかかりしとき➡
When a great disaster befalls this land,
異界より 爪楊枝をたずさえし
勇者が現れ この地を救わん｡
heroes carrying toothpicks will travel from
another world to save our world!
もしやと思うが そなたたちは…｡
いや もう何も言うまい｡
Perhaps you all are...
No, I say no more.
How could I ask someone else to fight for the sake
of a kingdom on the verge of destruction?!
滅亡を待つだけの国がために
ともに戦おうなどと➡
誰が言えようか…｡
言えようかって
もうとっくに口にしてるｱﾙ｡
Except you just said that out loud.
あのおっさん ﾀｲﾂから
何から何まで 白白しいね｡
This old man's got no shame, and I'm
not just talking about the bodysuit.
おい まどろっこしいんだよ
｢ｽﾍﾟ… じじい｣｡
[Note: Bleep covers "sperm."]
Hey, you're pretty slow, old Spe**.
前置きはいいから
敗残兵 全部よこせ｡
Enough introductions. Just hand
over your remaining soldiers.
あと 宝物庫の宝も
すべて軍資金として献上しろ｡
And give us whatever's in your treasure
vault for our war chest.
勇者どころか まるで
盗賊なんですけど この人たち｡
We sound more like thieves than heroes.
Amazing.
なんと！
ともに戦ってくれると申すか！
Are you offering to fight on our side?
やはり 我が目に狂いはなかった｡
My eyes did not betray me!
そなたたちこそ
伝説の勇者 一寸法師！
You must be the heroic
midgets of legend!
しかし 我が国は戦で疲弊し➡
But our kingdom has suffered from the long
war and we have no soldiers to offer you.
軍を貸す余裕はない｡
ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬぬかすな！
Don't give me that bull!
そこの衛兵二人と
お前がいるだろうが｡
There are two guards here, plus you!
馬車馬のように ｺｷ使ってやる｡
I'll abuse you like a workhorse.
ちょっと
やめてください 銀さん！
Hey! Stop that, Gin-san!
I shall offer one of the
strongest soldiers of the
せめてもの旅の助けに
我が白血球国最強の兵士を➡
Leukocyte Kingdom to aid
you in your journey.
一人だけ 供に授けよう｡
えっ ﾎﾝﾄですか!?
Really?
いでよ！ 白血球のﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙﾄﾞﾗｺﾞﾝと
恐れられる二強！
Come forth!
The strongest pair around, feared
as the Leukocyte Double Dragon!
戦士ﾎﾞﾙﾃｶﾞ！ 武闘家ﾃﾞｽﾋﾟｶﾞﾛ!!
The warrior, Bortega!
[Note: Parody of Ortega and Despisaro
from Dragon Quest III.]
The fighter, Despigaro!
(３人)あっ！
どちらでも
好きなほうを連れていくがよい｡
Take whichever one you want.
どっちもいらないんですけど～！
We don't want either of them!
おい～！ これ どこが
ﾀﾞﾌﾞﾙﾄﾞﾗｺﾞﾝなんだよ！
Hey!
How can you call them Double Dragon?!
どこが最強なんだよ！
なんで ﾎﾞﾙﾃｶﾞの後ろで➡
How can you call them
the strongest pair?!
Why is there someone who looks like
the prince crying behind Bortega?!
王子らしき人物が泣いてるんだよ｡
お前 これ完全に➡
You're obviously trying to get
rid of a dog the prince took in!
王子 拾ってきた犬
捨てようとしてんだろうが！
うぅ… 連れて… いくの？
Are you taking it...?
行かない！ 連れていかないから！
We aren't! We aren't taking it!
ﾎﾞﾙﾃｶﾞは ｲﾔか｡ じゃあ お母さん…｡
So you don't want Bortega...
Then take Moth-
ﾃﾞｽﾋﾟｶﾞﾛのほうを連れていくがいい｡
I mean, Despigaro
お母さん!?
今 お母さんって言いかけたよ！
Mother?!
You were about to say "Mother"!
ﾃﾞｽﾋﾟｶﾞﾛを お母さんって言ったよ！
You called Despigaro "Mother"!
おい とんでもねえよ
このおっさん｡
Hey, you've got some nerve, old man.
お母さんの面倒みるのｲﾔで➡
You trying to ditch your mother
off on the party of heroes
because you don't want
to take care of her?
勇者のﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰに
身売りしようとしやがったよ｡
とんでもないﾔﾂね｡
ｳｲﾙｽより ﾀﾁが悪いｱﾙ｡
Unbelievable. He's worse
than those viruses.
まず ｺｲﾂから
駆除したほうがいいね｡
We should eliminate him first.
待って 待って 待って！
違う 違う！
Wait! Wait! Wait!
No! No!
そういうんじゃない！
全然誤解 まったく誤解！
That's wrong! You've got it all wrong!
いや ﾏｼﾞ勘弁してくださいよ 旦那｡
Give me a break, big guy.
たまに 学校の先生とかに
｢お母さん｣って➡
You know how people accidentally call
their teacher "Mother" sometimes?
間違って呼んじゃうとき
あるっしょ？ あれっす いやﾏｼﾞで｡
That's what it was! For real!
なんかもう全然
王様じゃないんですけど｡
You're not even acting
like a king anymore.
そのへんのﾁﾝﾋﾟﾗみたいに
なってるんですけど｡
More like a common thug!
確かに最近 嫁と➡
It's true that I've been fighting with my
wife about how to take care of Mother.
お母さんの世話のことで
ｹﾝｶしましたよ｡
It's true there was an uproar because
Takeshi brought home a mutt.
確かに最近 たけしが
きったねえ雑種犬拾ってきて➡
ｹﾝｶしましたよ｡
でも それとこれとは全然違う｡
But none of that has anything to do
with what we're discussing here!
違わねえだろ！
思いっきり ﾘﾝｸしてんだろうが！
Except it does.
It's obviously related!
完全に 厄介払いしようと
してんだろうが！
You're obviously trying to dump
your problems off on us!
いや 違うんです！
この二人ね 今でこそ➡
No! You're wrong!
These two, you see...
They may look like this now,
こんな姿になってますが
実は ｳｲﾙｽに呪いをかけられて➡
but that's because they were
cursed by the virus!
こんな姿に
変えられてしまったんですよ！
真実を映し出すという
ﾊﾟｰの鏡さえ探し出せば➡
If you can find the Poof Mirror
that reveals the truth,
[Note: Parody of Rah Mirror
from Dragon Quest series.]
元の姿に戻って
即戦力になります！
they'll return to their original
forms and serve you well!
即使えます！ ぜひ お試しあれ！
Very well! Please give it a try!
なにが ﾊﾟｰの鏡だ！
ﾊﾟｰなのは お前だろ！
What's this Poof Mirror crap?
Your head's gone poof!
いや ﾏｼﾞっすって！
No! I'm serious!
ﾊﾟｰの鏡さえあればなぁ｡
見せてあげられるのになぁ｡
If you had the Poof Mirror!
I could show you!
(たま)ありますよ｡
We have it.
ﾊﾟｰの鏡なら ここに｡
The Poof Mirror is right here.
なっ… それは いったい どこで!?
What?
Where did you get that...?
ここは 私の体内｡
We are inside my body.
Searching for an object is like
going through my pockets.
探し物など
ﾎﾟｹｯﾄの中を探るようなものです｡
獏は 高度な擬態能力を
備えていると聞きます｡
I've heard the Tapir are especially
skilled at mimicry.
目に見えるものを
そのまま信じていては➡
You cannot defeat the Tapir if you
believe everything you see.
獏には勝てません｡
さぁ どんな真実が映るのか｡
Now, let us see what truths
shall be revealed,
ﾎﾞﾙﾃｶﾞか ﾃﾞｽﾋﾟｶﾞﾛか
それとも 他の何かか｡
be it Bortega, Despigaro,
or something else...
皆さん とくとご覧ください｡
Everybody look closely.
こ… これは！ 王様… 王様が！
Th-This is...!
The King... The King...!
乳輪… 超でけえ｡
どうでもいい！ 死ぬほど！
His nipples...are huge!
Nobody cares! I swear!
いや ちょっと待って！
No! Wait a sec!
王様の乳輪が
どんどんでかくなっていきます！
The King's nipples ARE getting bigger!
｢ｵﾉ… ｺ｣ いや それ以上！
これは… これは！
Yo** **o...
[Note: Word play on "Oh no."
Bleep covers "Yoko Ono."]
No, even bigger!
This is... This is...!
ﾌﾌﾌ… なかなかやるではないか｡
Not too shabby.
[Leukocyte]
[Tapir]
う～ん… たぁ！
♪♪～
[Leukocyte]
[Tapir]
ﾌﾌﾌ… なかなかやるではないか｡
Not too shabby.
まさか この獏の擬態を
見破るとはな ｶﾞﾊﾊﾊ！
I never expected you to see
through this Tapir disguise!
あっ！
This is...
これは！ おい まさか これが獏!?
Hey! Don't tell me this is a Tapir!
全身ﾀｲﾂ 白から黒に
着替えただけじゃねえか！
He's just wearing a black bodysuit
instead of a white one!
んなこと言ってる場合ですか！
This isn't the time for that!
白血球国の王が すでに
ｳｲﾙｽにやられてるということは➡
If they've already gotten the Leukocyte
King, that means...
つまり…｡
Exactly.
そのとおり｡ 助けを求め
この国に足を運んだようだが➡
You came to this kingdom seeking aid,
ひと足遅かったな｡
but are too late.
すでに 白血球国は 王をはじめ
衛兵はもちろん…｡
The Leukocyte Kingdom, from
the king down to the soldiers...
Even Mother...
お母さんも｡
王子たけしも｡
Even Prince Takeshi...
♪♪～
国ごと 黒ﾀｲﾂ一色｡
The entire kingdom is in black bodysuits!
もうここに ｷｻﾏたちの
味方はいない！
You have no allies here!
We will consume all!
我らは すべてを喰らう！
すべてが 黒ﾀｲﾂになるまで➡
Until all are dressed in black bodysuits,
喰らいつくす！
we will continue to consume!
ﾁｯ！
うぅっ！
The toothpicks.
(たま)爪楊枝を｡
皆さん 爪楊枝を使ってください｡
Everyone take hold of your toothpicks!
その爪楊枝は源外様が
あつらえた特別製｡
Those toothpicks were specially
made by Gengai-sama.
情報を喰らう 獏の特性を利用し➡
They take advantage of the Tapir's
nature to consume data
by sending large quantities
of data at high speeds!
逆に 獏に大量の情報を
高速で送り込むものです｡
ん？ なんだ!?
Huh? What?
(たま)それも 食中毒を
引き起こすような 腐った情報を｡
And the data is rotten enough
to cause food poisoning.
毒を喰らい
ひきつけを起こした胃袋に➡
If you continue to send poison to their stomachs
after they've been poisoned once,
さらに 直接 毒を注ぎ続ければ➡
彼らの胃袋は
情報を消化する前に…｡
their stomachs will not have enough
time to digest the data
ﾊﾟﾝｸします｡
and they'll explode.
上等じゃねえか！
食べｶｽは取れねえが➡
That sounds just fine!
These toothpicks can't remove leftover
food stuck in your teeth,
but they can kick stinking
virus butt, huh?!
ﾁﾝｶｽｳｲﾙｽは取れる爪楊枝ってか！
銀さん 数が多すぎます！
Gin-san! There are too many!
全部は さばききれません！
We can't deal with all of them!
ほちゃ～！ てやぁ～！
早く こっちｱﾙ！
ここは いったん退くね｡
Hurry! This way!
We need to retreat for now!
Don't expect to escape!
逃がすと思うか！ ﾊｯ！
You're all going to die here!
ここで ｷｻﾏらは死ぬのだ！
ｷｻﾏは 何を!? んっ!?
What are you...?!
これは！
This is...!
ﾊﾟｰの鏡よ 真実を照らし出せ｡
Poof Mirror, reveal the truth!
我を護りし 比類なき勇者に
再び剣を！
Return the sword to the hero who
protects me as no other can!
That's...!
あれは！
犬が！
The dog is...!
Turning into a person...
人に…｡
ｷ ｷｻﾏは～！
Y-You're...!
人ではありません｡
あれこそが…｡
That is not a person.
That is...
うわぁ～っ！
(たま)数多のｳｲﾙｽを討ち滅ぼし➡
The ultimate security program that
has destroyed many viruses
私の体内の平和を護り続けてきた
最強のｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑ…｡
and kept the peace in my body.
正真正銘 本物の 白血球王です｡
The one and only true...
Leukocyte King!
(３人)あっ！
ぎ… 銀さん!?
Gi...
Gin-san?!
捜せ！
どこ行った!?
Find them!
Were they there?
おい いたか!?
そっちか!?
知らん 知らない！
Where'd they go?!
Damn! Where did they go?
ｸｿｯ！ どこいった ﾔﾂらめ！
捜せ！ 鼻毛の根を分けてでも
捜し出すんだ！
Find them! Even if you have
to split nose hairs!
行ったようだな｡
Looks like they're gone.
Lady Tama, they will find us here.
たま様 ここも 気づかれましょう｡
We should move at once.
すぐに 移動しましょう｡
大腸 Ｂ29地区方面が
よろしいかと｡
I believe B-29 in the large
intestine would be safe.
あそこは 迷路です｡
身を隠すには うってつけだ｡
That place is a maze.
Perfect for hiding out in.
Leukocyte King, we did not
come here to escape.
We came to fight.
たとえ ｺﾋﾟｰといえど➡
Though you may only be a copy,
たま様を 雑菌どもの中には
さらせません｡
I cannot allow Lady Tama
near those filthy viruses.
戦うなら ｵﾚ一人で 十分です｡
I can handle the fighting alone.
(たま)白血球王 今回の敵は
最強のｳｲﾙｽです｡
Leukocyte King.
This time we are up against
the strongest virus ever.
今までのようには いきません｡
The battle will not be as simple
as it has been in the past.
あなたといえども
一人では ﾑﾘです｡
Even someone as accomplished as
yourself will have no chance alone.
We must work together and fight.
みんなで 協力して戦いましょう｡
So you were the one who rewrote my
program and turned me into that dog.
やはり ｵﾚのﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑを書き換え➡
あんな 犬の姿に変えたのは
あなたでしたか｡
You restricted my ability to act so I wouldn't
attempt to face them alone.
ｵﾚが一人でﾔﾂらに戦いを挑み
ﾑﾀﾞ死にせぬよう動きを封じた｡
そうでしょ？
Is that correct?
Your death would be an inconvenience.
When the right time finally came...
Yes, I wished for you to survive
to fight alongside us.
What's your problem?
さっきからなんなんだ ｷｻﾏは？
雑菌だらけの顔を
たま様に近づけるな｡
Keep that virus-infested face
away from Lady Tama.
殺菌されたいのか？
いやぁ ごめん｡
You wanna get sterilized?
No, sorry.
すっごいいい男がいるなぁと
思って見とれちゃって…｡
I couldn't help but stare at
such a handsome face...
なわけねえだろ！
Not!
ｵﾚは
ﾓｼｬｽかけられた覚えはねえぞ！
I don't recall ever having a Transform
spell cast on me.
人さまの顔ぶらさげて
恥ずかしいｺｽﾌﾟﾚしやがってよ｡
You've got nerve to do that embarrassing
cosplay with my face!
ﾛﾄ気取りか？ あんｺﾗ！
[Note: Loto is the legendary hero from Dragon Quest 3.]
You think you're Loto?!
A lot of people in this world claim
that DQ3 was the best one,
世の中には
Ⅲがﾄﾞﾗｸｴ 最高傑作なんていう➡
声も多いが
ｵﾚは そんなん認めねえ！
but I won't accept that!
There are two Gin-chans.
銀ちゃんが 二人ｱﾙ｡
Ta-Tama-san, what is that?
たまさん いったい
なんなんですか あれ？
なんであの人
銀さんと同じ容姿を？
Why does that guy look like Gin-san?
All internal systems are affected
by my memory banks,
thought patterns, and various other data.
I would assume that image
was influenced by my mind.
(たま)あの姿は 私のｲﾒｰｼﾞが
反映された結果だと思われます｡
つまり？
あらゆるｳｲﾙｽと戦う
ｾｷｭﾘﾃｨｰﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑ 白血球は➡
Meaning...?
The security program Leukocyte, which
combats all sorts of viruses,
なにより強い存在でなくては
いけません｡
is a reflection of the strongest
person I know.
That would be the most
accurate conclusion.
Hey!
(たま)最強の二人が揃いました｡
もう恐れるものはありません｡
Two of the strongest have
been assembled.
There is nothing to fear now.
そうか｡ ｷｻﾏがｵﾚの…｡
I see. So you're my...
ともあれ 人格ﾃﾞｰﾀが
こうも違うところを見るに➡
Though the significant difference
in personality between us
内面は評価されていないようだな｡
んだと！
suggests she doesn't think much
of what's in your head.
What was that?!
当然だ｡ こんな腑抜けた男｡
Though that's a given, considering
how much of a coward you are.
そんな雑菌まみれの手では➡
You won't be able to protect Lady Tama
with those virus-infested hands.
たま様を護ることなど
できはしない｡
獏を倒すのは このｵﾚだ｡
I shall be the one to defeat the Tapir.
ｷｻﾏの出る幕などありはしない｡
There is no need for you to step in.
たま様を護れるのは ｵﾚだけだ｡
I am the only one who can
protect Lady Tama.
[To Be Continued]
[The next episode...]
My lord, Archfiend Tapir.
I just received word that Bifidus Castle
and E. coli Castle have been taken.
Is that so?
The areas of greatest resistance
now belong to our forces.
Very soon, the system of this world
will fall completely into Tapir hands.
The super science and technology poured
into this robot meant nothing.
Nothing can stop us now.
Excellency!
What is all the fuss about?
The third Tapir general was somehow
destroyed in the Leukocyte Kingdom.
What? That's impossible.
The Leukocyte Kingdom was
completely under our control
without a single Leukocyte left to resist.
Nobody left in this world
can stand against us.
According to our information,
there was an incredibly strong Leukocyte
dressed up like he was in Dragon Quest.
獏大魔王閣下｡
ﾋﾞﾌｨｽﾞｽ菌城 大腸菌城
ともに先ほど落城したとの情報が｡
Along with three human-like creatures
carrying toothpicks
(獏大魔王)そうか｡
and a pixel robot to fill out the party.
これで主だった反抗勢力は
すべて➡
D-Dragon Quest, you say?!
我が軍門に下ったというわけだ｡
C-Could it be?!
He's... He's still alive?!
間もなくこの世界のｼｽﾃﾑは
我ら獏の手に完全に落ちる｡
Deliver this order to all soldiers
in this robot!
超科学技術で作られた
からくりとやらも このｻﾞﾏだ｡
Return to the Archfiend
Tapir's castle at once!
Abandon any conquered
castles if necessary!
もはや 我らを止められるものは
どこにもいない｡
Concentrate all forces at his castle immediately
and tighten the defenses!
閣下｡
なにごとだ｡ 騒がしい｡
Sir!
白血球国の獏第三将軍が
何者かの手によって➡
Is it him?
駆除されました｡
なに？ ﾊﾞｶな？
Yes...
He's coming...
白血球国はすでに完全制圧し➡
逆らう白血球は一匹残らず
根絶やしにしたはず｡
The Leukocyte King,
この世界に 我らに
歯向かえるものなど もう…｡
with a party of heroes from the outside
world, is headed towards this castle!
情報によれば ﾄﾞﾗｸｴのｺｽﾌﾟﾚをした
恐ろしく強い白血球が一匹｡
["A Group of Fools are Led"]
[The five fools are led to and storm
the Archfiend Tapir's castle!]
そして 爪楊枝を携えた
生身の人間らしき者が三人｡
ﾄﾞｯﾄ絵のからくりが
一匹のﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰらしいのですが｡
[Will Gin-san and the Leukocyte King
work well with one another?]
ﾄﾞ ﾄﾞﾗｸｴだと？ ま まさか ﾔﾂが➡
[See you next time.]
ﾔﾂが生きていたというのか？
体内に散らばる兵たちに下知せよ｡
ただちに
この獏大魔王城に帰還せよと｡
制圧した城など放棄してかまわぬ｡
ただちに 全軍をこの城に集結させ
守りにつかせるのだ｡
はっ｡
ﾔﾂか｡
はい｡ ﾔﾂが来ます｡
白血球王が
外界から勇者たちをﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰに加え➡
この城に…｡